indivisible.org 2019-06-13

# Indivisible Privacy Policy | Indivisible

_Effective: March 5, 2019_

To see our previous privacy policy, click here.

Indivisible values your privacy and we strive to provide you with a safe and secure user experience.   This Privacy Policy describes the information we collect from the Indivisible network and Websites about you, and how we use, disclose and protect that information.  This Privacy Policy applies to our website, indivisible.org, and any other websites, applications, and online services that link to this privacy policy (the “Websites”) regardless of how you access or use them, including through mobile devices.  This Privacy Policy also applies to the information we collect from volunteers of the Indivisible network, which may include information collected through the Websites, or in person by group leaders within the Indivisible network from prospective volunteers and supporters when canvassing or attending community events.

By using our Websites, you are accepting the terms of this Privacy Policy and our terms of use, and you are consenting to our information collection, use, and disclosure practices, as described in this Privacy Policy. By providing us or the Indivisible volunteers with your contact information you are also consenting to the terms of this Privacy Policy.  If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use our Websites or provide the Indivisible network with your information.  At any time, you may choose to contact us to remove your information from our system.   

We may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time.  We will post any changes to our Websites. Your continued use of our Websites and the Indivisible network services following the posting of any changes will mean you accept those changes.

This Privacy Policy applies to any site that directly links to it, and to information we collect when you interact with us through social media and similar online services.  This policy does not apply to information that you may submit to us offline or to third-party websites and mobile applications that may link to the Websites or be linked to on the Websites. We are not responsible for the actions or privacy practices of third-party websites and applications; please consult those websites and applications directly to understand their privacy practices. Before using the social features of Indivisible’s Facebook group, please consult Facebook’s terms of service [ **here**](https://www.facebook.com/terms).

Information We Collect 

How We Use Information

How We Share Information with Others

How We Use Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

[Your](https://docs.google.com/document/d/1CoeMYqud2S8SZqiFgh6-4oZaaCKZNq4oOkvUii8f0MI/edit?ts=5bbf7f3d#bookmark=id.tyjcwt) Choices

How We Secure Information

Other Important Information

Questions or Report a Problem

## INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We collect, process, and retain information from you and any devices you may use when you use or interact with our Websites, and in other ways described below.

_**Information You Give Us:**_   We receive and store information you enter on our Websites or give us or Indivisible network volunteers in any other way.  For example, when you register to receive updates, sign up to volunteer, make donations, or complete a form or survey, we may ask you to provide us with information such as your name, email address, mailing address or ZIP code, phone number, or payment information.  We also collect information when Indivisible network volunteers register groups on the Websites, or when you answer survey questions by voice calls or text messages or through any of our web services.

_**Information We Automatically Collect:**_  We collect information about your use of our Websites, such as the donations you make, the pages you view, and other interactions you have.  We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with our Websites. Our Websites use “cookies,” tagging, and other tracking technologies to help enable us to enhance or personalize your online browsing experience.  This information includes computer and connection information such as statistics on your page views, traffic to and from our Websites, referral URL, ad data, your IP address, and device identifiers. This information also may include your browsing history, transaction history, and your web log information.

_**Information from Social Media:**_  When you interact with us or our Websites on a social media platform, we may collect the personal information that you make available to us on that page, including your account ID or username and other information included in your posts.  If you choose to log in to your account with or through a social networking service, we and that service may share certain information about you and your activities.

**_Information from Other Sources:_**  We may supplement the personal information we collect with information from third parties and add it to your account information.  This information may include, but is not limited to, demographic information that is publically available, additional contact information, group affiliations, occupational information, and educational background.

## HOW WE USE INFORMATION

We use your information to help us personalize and continually improve your experience on the Websites, including fulfilling requests for information and communicating with you, including connecting you with other users when you do things like host meetings or create events.

We also may use your information to provide, maintain, and improve the Websites and for internal or other purposes; optimize or improve our Websites, products, services and operations; track and evaluate the use of the Websites, including performing statistical, demographic, and marketing analyses; send you information about features and enhancements on or to our Websites; and detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may violate our policies or be fraudulent or illegal.

If you choose to provide us with additional information through our surveys (conducted by phone, text, or web) we may use that information internally to better target our communications, build out our databases, and integrate our tools.  We may use the information you provide us internally, and also share your responses with Indivisible network groups, their leaders and third parties closely associated with our organization to help us improve our outreach and support.

We may use the information from one portion of the Websites on other portions of the Websites, and we may combine information gathered from multiple portions of the Websites into a single record.  We also may use or combine information that we collect offline or that we collect or receive from local Indivisible network groups, and third-party sources for many reasons, including to enhance, expand, and check the accuracy of our records. Additionally, information collected from a particular browser or device may be used with another computer or device that is linked to the browser or device on which such information was collected.

For information about how to manage your information and the choices you have, see Your Choices below.

## HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION WITH OTHERS

When you provide information that personally identifies you to the team of volunteers, staff, and contractors who run Indivisible Project, we appreciate the sensitivities that may be associated with that.  We will not share your personally identifiable information with anyone else without your consent except in limited circumstances, as described below. We may, however, share information that does not specifically and personally identify you, such as aggregate information, device identifiers, or other unique identifiers to third parties.  For information about how to manage your information and the choices you have, see Your Choices below.  

Please note, that some of the information you provide, such as when you register groups or create events, is public and your information will be publicly available to others who visit or use the Websites.

Third-Party Service Providers:  We engage third-party service providers to perform functions on our behalf such as: hosting, content management, analytics, and fraud protection.  These third parties may have access to your personal information when needed to perform their functions. If we share information with these third parties that personally identifies you, such as your name, address, or phone number, we will require the third parties to maintain the confidentiality and security of your personal information, and they will be restricted from using, selling, or distributing such personally identifiable information in any way other than to provide the requested services to the Websites or as otherwise required or expressly permitted by law.  

Indivisible network groups: We regularly provide supporter and volunteer lists to Invisible network groups (made up of local community volunteers) within the Indivisible network.  The Indivisible network is a nationwide movement of thousands of volunteer-led local groups that engage in a range of progressive efforts ranging from advocacy to electoral work at the local, state, and federal level.  At the national level, Indivisible is supported by three separate entities: Indivisible Civics, a 501(c)(3) non-profit organization; Indivisible Project, a 501(c)(4) non-profit organization; and Indivisible Action, a hybrid political action committee. When volunteers and supporters of Indivisible sign up to attend events, participate locally, or receive information from Indivisible, the contact information shared with the national Indivisible organizations may be shared with Indivisible network groups in the relevant locality. For instance, if you sign up to attend an event in your community, we will share your registration information with the local Indivisible network group organizing the event.  Sharing your contact information with Indivisible network groups may be necessary for administrative matters, or to provide you with additional information about local events and related information.  If you prefer that we do not share your name and contact information with Indivisible network groups, please let us know by following the instructions in the opt-out procedures below.  If you have any questions about this type of sharing, please contact us at [**contact@indivisible.org**](mailto:contact@indivisible.org) **.**

Partners: We occasionally exchange or share our supporter lists with carefully selected organizations whose information we believe may be of interest to our supporters.  Sharing your name with other similar organizations or businesses will help us build our supporter base and expand our programs in a cost-effective way. If you prefer that we do not exchange or share your name and contact information, please let us know by following the instructions in the opt-out procedures below.

Mergers and Transfers:  We may change control of our organization, transfer assets, or merge with another entity while providing the Websites.  We may transfer the information we collect and maintain to another entity or its affiliates or service providers in connection with, or during negotiations of, any such change, transfer or merger.  Under such circumstances, we will require the acquiring party to follow the practices described in this Privacy Statement with respect to previously collected information.

Law Enforcement, Legal Process, and Emergency Situations:  We may also use or disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or on the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to applicable law or comply with legal process served on us or our Websites; (b) protect and defend our rights or property, the Websites or our users, or (c) act to protect the personal safety of us, users of the Websites, or the public.

For example, if you post information to the Websites, we may disclose your information to a third party that alleges that you have infringed their intellectual property rights.  Similarly, if you allege that another user of the Websites is infringing upon your intellectual property rights, we may disclose your information to the alleged infringer.

## How We Use Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

Like many websites, we use tracking technologies such as cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies to record your preferences, and track the use of our Websites.  We may also use these technologies to monitor traffic, and improve the Websites. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies but, if you prefer, you can usually modify your browser setting to disable or reject cookies. If you delete your cookies or if you set your browser to decline cookies, some features of the Websites may not work or may not work as designed.

We partner with third-party advertising companies who also use these tracking tools to provide advertisements on our Websites or other websites.  These third parties may use these technologies to collect information about you when you use the Websites. They may collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites and other online services.  They may also use persistent identifiers to track your Internet usage across other websites in their networks beyond the Websites. They may use this information to provide you with interest-based advertising or other targeted content.  While we do not knowingly provide these entities with information that personally identifies you such third parties may, with sufficient data from other sources, be able to personally identify you, unknown to us.

Your browser or device may include “Do Not Track” functionality.  Our information collection and disclosure practices, and the choices that we provide to visitors, will continue to operate as described in this Privacy Statement, whether or not a Do Not Track signal is received.

## YOUR CHOICES

When you sign up for communications from us, register a group, or register an action, you acknowledge that we may use your e-mail address to communicate with you about our activities and respond to your inquiries, as well as take any other actions associated with your requests. You may unsubscribe from communications by using the unsubscribe mechanism provided in those communications.  Please note that we may still need to retain information previously provided to comply with legal obligations.

Online Tracking Choices:  You also have choices to limit some tracking mechanisms that collect information when you use the Websites.  Many web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser’s setting to decline cookies if you prefer.  If you choose to decline cookies, certain features of our Websites, including the Websites themselves, may not function properly or remain accessible to you.  In addition, you may also render some web beacons unusable by rejecting or removing their associated cookies.

We use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc., on our Websites. Google Analytics uses cookies or other tracking technologies to help us analyze how users interact with and use the Websites, compile reports on the Websites’ activity, and provide other services related to Websites activity and usage.  The technologies used by Google may collect information such as your IP address, time of visit, whether you are a return visitor, and any referring website. The Websites do not use Google Analytics to gather information that personally identifies you. The information generated by Google Analytics will be transmitted to and stored by Google and will be subject to Google’s [privacy policies](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). To learn more about Google’s partner services and to learn how to opt out of tracking of analytics by Google click [here](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).

Many of the third party advertisers that place tracking tools on our Websites are members of programs that offer you additional choices regarding the collection and use of your information.  You can learn more about the options available to limit these third parties’ collection and use of your information by visiting the websites for the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) and the [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.youradchoices.com/aboutus.aspx).  You can also learn more about [Facebook’s ad preferences tool](https://www.facebook.com/help/247395082112892) and [manage your preferences](https://www.facebook.com/ads/settings).

Please note that opting-out of advertising networks services does not mean that you will not receive advertising while using our Websites or on other websites, nor will it prevent the receipt of interest-based advertising from third parties that do not participate in these programs.  It will, however, exclude you from interest-based advertising conducted through participating networks, as provided by their policies and choice mechanisms.

Communications: We send subscribers information about upcoming events in their local region, as well as updates and informational resources as they become available. If you do not wish to receive emails about such events, resources, or other service offerings you may opt-out by clicking the opt-out button at the bottom of the email. We may send you communications via text messages from time to time.  You may opt-in to receive such text messages through our mobile phone program. If you believe you have received and email or text message in error, please email us at [contact@indivisible.org](mailto:contact@indivisible.org).

Periodically you may also receive account related emails that include confirmations of your registration for an event or group, transactional emails related to donations, or other significant notifications related to our service or your participation in activities.  Please note that you may communicate with us via email, but be aware that information disclosed in emails may not be secure or encrypted and as a result may be available to others. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose confidential or sensitive information through email. If you contact us via email, we will use your email address to respond directly to your questions or comments.

## HOW WE SECURE YOUR INFORMATION

We do our best to provide you with a safe and secure experience when you use our website.  Our Websites incorporate physical, technical, and administrative procedures to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal information, including the use of encryption, firewalls, limited access and other controls where appropriate.   Please understand, however, that while we do our best to safeguard your personal information once we receive it, no transmission of data over the Internet or any other public network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.

You can help protect the privacy of your own information by using encryption and other techniques to prevent unauthorized interception of your personal information.  You are responsible for the security of your information that you transmit to us or view, download, or otherwise access when using unencrypted, public or otherwise unsecured networks.

## OTHER IMPORTANT INFORMATION

Users under Thirteen:  Our Websites are intended for users ages 13 and older only.  Accordingly, we will not knowingly collect or use any personal information from children that we know to be under the age of 13.  If we learn that a child under the age of 13 has provided us with personal information, we will delete it in accordance with applicable law.

Users Outside of the United States:  If you use our Websites outside of the United States, you understand and consent to the transfer of your personal information to, and the collection, processing, and storage of your personal information in, the United States and elsewhere.  The laws in the U.S. and these countries regarding personal information may be different than the laws of your state or country.

Your California Privacy Rights:  We do not disclose your personal information to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes unless you consent to such disclosures.

## QUESTIONS OR REPORT A PROBLEM

For questions about our Privacy Statement, to make choices about receiving promotional communications, to update your personal information, or to place an order, you can contact us by email at [contact@indivisible](mailto:contact@indivisible.org).org.

## INDIVISIBLE COOKIE POLICY

Our Websites rely on partners to provide many features of our sites and services using data about your use of our Websites. Below is a list of these partners with links to more information their use of your data and how to exercise your rights to opt-out.

### Site Operations

Enabling features that are necessary for providing you the services on our Websites, tracking content views, remembering your preferences, and enabling visibility into whether you signed up for updates.

Partner

| 

Learn more about their use of data:  
  
---|---  
  
Google Tag Manager

| 

<https://policies.google.com/privacy>  
  
### Analytics

Allowing us to understand how our services are being used, track site performance and make improvements.

Partner

| 

Learn more about their use of data:  
  
---|---  
  
Google Analytics

| 

<https://policies.google.com/privacy>  
  
New Relic

| 

<https://newrelic.com/termsandconditions/privacy>  
  
### Advertising

Delivering advertising, including tailored advertising based on your preferences or interests across services and devices; and measuring the effectiveness of advertisements.

Partner

| 

Learn more about their use of data, and how to Opt-out from data use:  
  
---|---  
  
DoubleClick for Publishers

| 

<https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>

<https://adssettings.google.com/>  
  
Facebook Pixel and Custom Audience

| 

<https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217>  
  
### Social Media

Enabling the sharing of content from our services through social networking and other sites, and allowing you to interact and connect with such social media sites while using our Websites.

Partner

| 

Learn more about their use of data, and how to Opt-out from data use:  
  
---|---  
  
Facebook Connect

| 

Twitter Connect

| 

<https://twitter.com/en/privacy>  
  
Twitter Syndication

| 

<https://twitter.com/en/privacy>
